<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<Database>
	<EnglishText>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_TIER1_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Metropolis Ascendant (size 1): +1 Specialist per district, and +[icon:YIELD_HAPPINESS] Happiness to help this dense Settlement hold a higher Happiness stage.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_STAGE_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>While this Settlement is Joyous or happier: +[icon:YIELD_SCIENCE] Science and +[icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture per Urban [icon:YIELD_POPULATION] Population, increasing further while Ecstatic. A perfected metropolis turns its happiness into output. Full only while you stay tall (one city per hemisphere).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_TIER2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Metropolis Ascendant (size 2): +1 Specialist per district; +Wonder production; +Great Work slots in the Palace.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_TIER3_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Metropolis Ascendant (size 3): +1 Specialist per district; +[icon:YIELD_SCIENCE] Science and +[icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture per Urban [icon:YIELD_POPULATION] Population.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_SAFETY_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Specialists cost 50% less [icon:YIELD_FOOD] Food and [icon:YIELD_HAPPINESS] Happiness to maintain, so a city packed with Specialists stays stable. Active while you hold fewer than 5 Cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_SLOTS_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>+1 flexible Great Work slot in every building and Wonder that has one, so a single city can store all the Codices, Relics, Artifacts and Great Works a victory needs. Counts all settlements: requires fewer than 4 total settlements (Towns included).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW">
			<Text>+{1_Value} Organized Military</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_RESEED_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>New Age head start: +[icon:YIELD_SCIENCE] Science and +[icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture per Urban [icon:YIELD_POPULATION] Population while your empire rebuilds. Active from the start of the Age until you research this Age's main bonus node, then your full bonuses take over. Fades as you add settlements; ends at four.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_ARCADIA_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Arcadia: a Breathtaking rural tile gains [icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture, [icon:YIELD_PRODUCTION] Production, [icon:YIELD_HAPPINESS] Happiness, [icon:YIELD_SCIENCE] Science and [icon:YIELD_FOOD] Food (more in later Ages). Awakened by discovering a Natural Wonder; your own Wonders raise nearby Appeal, so cluster them in lush land to push tiles to Breathtaking.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_ARCADIA_PEAKS_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Arcadia (the peaks): a worked Mountain tile gains [icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture, [icon:YIELD_PRODUCTION] Production, [icon:YIELD_HAPPINESS] Happiness, [icon:YIELD_SCIENCE] Science and [icon:YIELD_FOOD] Food (more in later Ages) - the same bounty as a Breathtaking tile. Once Arcadia awakens you may terrace Mountains to work them, and every Building beside a Mountain gains [icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture and [icon:YIELD_GOLD] Gold - turning the peaks that once capped your metropolis into its crown.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Per-age, per-domain unlock notes (LOC_MA_<AQ|EX|MO>_NOTE_*) are GENERATED with live numbers into
		     MetropolisAscendantNotes.generated.xml by tools/gen-ascendant.ps1 - do not add them here. -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_UNLOCK_NOTE">
			<Text>Metropolis Ascendant unlocked. As your Urban [icon:YIELD_POPULATION] Population grows, a single tall city gains escalating bonuses tied to where you research them across the tech and culture trees: more Specialist slots, larger [icon:YIELD_SCIENCE] Science and [icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture adjacency, yields per Population, extra Great Work slots, faster Wonder production, and Suzerain bonuses that scale with the city-states you lead. Build Wonders to enrich the metropolis: adjacent Buildings gain [icon:YIELD_HAPPINESS] Happiness and your Wonders raise the Appeal of the surrounding land - and once you discover a Natural Wonder, [B]Arcadia[/B] awakens: every Breathtaking rural tile flourishes with [icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture, [icon:YIELD_PRODUCTION] Production, [icon:YIELD_HAPPINESS] Happiness, [icon:YIELD_SCIENCE] Science and [icon:YIELD_FOOD] Food, and you may terrace Mountains to work them for [icon:YIELD_PRODUCTION] Production, [icon:YIELD_SCIENCE] Science and [icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture. Bonuses fade as you add settlements (Towns included) and end at four.</Text>
		</Row>
	</EnglishText>
</Database>
