<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<Database>
	<EnglishText>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_TIER1_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Metropolis Ascendant (size 1): +1 Specialist per district, and +[icon:YIELD_HAPPINESS] Happiness to help this dense Settlement hold a higher Happiness stage.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_STAGE_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>While this Settlement is Joyous or happier: +[icon:YIELD_SCIENCE] Science and +[icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture per Urban [icon:YIELD_POPULATION] Population, increasing further while Ecstatic. A perfected metropolis turns its happiness into output. Full only while you stay tall (one city per hemisphere).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_TIER2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Metropolis Ascendant (size 2): +1 Specialist per district; +Wonder production; +Great Work slots in the Palace.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_TIER3_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Metropolis Ascendant (size 3): +1 Specialist per district; +[icon:YIELD_SCIENCE] Science and +[icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture per Urban [icon:YIELD_POPULATION] Population.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_SAFETY_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Specialists cost 50% less [icon:YIELD_FOOD] Food and [icon:YIELD_HAPPINESS] Happiness to maintain, so a city packed with Specialists stays stable. Active while you hold fewer than 5 Cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_SLOTS_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>+1 flexible Great Work slot in every building and Wonder that has one, so a single city can store all the Codices, Relics, Artifacts and Great Works a victory needs. Counts all settlements: requires fewer than 4 total settlements (Towns included).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW">
			<Text>+{1_Value} Organized Military</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_RESEED_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>New Age head start: +[icon:YIELD_SCIENCE] Science and +[icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture per Urban [icon:YIELD_POPULATION] Population while your empire rebuilds. Active from the start of the Age until you research this Age's main bonus node, then your full bonuses take over. Fades as you add settlements; ends at four.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_ARCADIA_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Arcadia: a Breathtaking rural tile gains [icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture, [icon:YIELD_PRODUCTION] Production, [icon:YIELD_HAPPINESS] Happiness, [icon:YIELD_SCIENCE] Science and [icon:YIELD_FOOD] Food (more in later Ages). Awakened by discovering a Natural Wonder; your own Wonders raise nearby Appeal, so cluster them in lush land to push tiles to Breathtaking.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_ARCADIA_PEAKS_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Arcadia (the peaks): a worked Mountain tile gains [icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture, [icon:YIELD_PRODUCTION] Production, [icon:YIELD_HAPPINESS] Happiness, [icon:YIELD_SCIENCE] Science and [icon:YIELD_FOOD] Food (more in later Ages) - the same bounty as a Breathtaking tile. Once Arcadia awakens you may terrace Mountains to work them, and every Building beside a Mountain gains [icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture and [icon:YIELD_GOLD] Gold - turning the peaks that once capped your metropolis into its crown.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_ARCADIA_WATERS_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Arcadia (the waters): once Arcadia awakens, the metropolis draws bounty from the surrounding water. Each worked water tile yields by type - Navigable Rivers give [icon:YIELD_FOOD] Food and [icon:YIELD_GOLD] Gold, Lakes give [icon:YIELD_FOOD] Food and [icon:YIELD_HAPPINESS] Happiness, the open sea gives [icon:YIELD_FOOD] Food, [icon:YIELD_GOLD] Gold and [icon:YIELD_SCIENCE] Science, Reefs give [icon:YIELD_SCIENCE] Science and [icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture, and water Natural Wonders give a large spike (more in later Ages). Buildings beside Coast gain [icon:YIELD_GOLD] Gold and beside a Navigable River gain [icon:YIELD_PRODUCTION] Production. In Exploration you may work the open ocean, and a coastal city gains a flat [icon:YIELD_FOOD] Food and [icon:YIELD_PRODUCTION] Production floor just for sitting on the sea - so even a single tile-starved island can feed a metropolis.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Per-age, per-domain unlock notes (LOC_MA_<AQ|EX|MO>_NOTE_*) are GENERATED with live numbers into
		     MetropolisAscendantNotes.generated.xml by tools/gen-ascendant.ps1 - do not add them here. -->
		<!-- Victory-wonder recycle "Foundations" buildings (issue #1). The building/unlock/binding are GENERATED into
		     data/modern/recycle.xml; these player-facing strings are hand-authored. NAME shows in the production list
		     (Buildings section); DESCRIPTION/TOOLTIP show in the pop-out info panel. -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_RECLAIM_WORLDS_FAIR_NAME">
			<Text>World's Fair Foundations</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_RECLAIM_WORLDS_FAIR_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Lay the groundwork for the World's Fair on a tile you have already built up. When this Building completes, that tile becomes the [B]World's Fair[/B] - so a packed metropolis can still raise its victory Wonder with no open tiles left. Build it over an obsolete earlier-Age district to reclaim that tile. Available only once you can already build the World's Fair (Cultural Hegemony mastery), and only while you remain a single dominant city. Costs the same as the Wonder; you also give up the Building it replaces.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_RECLAIM_WORLDS_FAIR_TOOLTIP">
			<Text>Build this over an obsolete earlier-Age district to reclaim that tile; when it completes, the tile becomes the [B]World's Fair[/B]. For a tile-starved tall metropolis with no open space left for the victory Wonder. Costs the same as the Wonder, and you give up the Building it replaces. Available once you can build the World's Fair (Cultural Hegemony mastery) and while you remain a single dominant city. Don't build it if you already own the World's Fair — it won't convert.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_RECLAIM_MANHATTAN_NAME">
			<Text>Manhattan Project Foundations</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_RECLAIM_MANHATTAN_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Lay the groundwork for the Manhattan Project on a tile you have already built up. When this Building completes, that tile becomes the [B]Manhattan Project[/B] - so a packed metropolis can still raise its victory Wonder with no open tiles left. Build it over an obsolete earlier-Age district to reclaim that tile. Available only once you can already build the Manhattan Project (Nuclear Fission), and only while you remain a single dominant city. Costs the same as the Wonder; you also give up the Building it replaces.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_RECLAIM_MANHATTAN_TOOLTIP">
			<Text>Build this over an obsolete earlier-Age district to reclaim that tile; when it completes, the tile becomes the [B]Manhattan Project[/B]. For a tile-starved tall metropolis with no open space left for the victory Wonder. Costs the same as the Wonder, and you give up the Building it replaces. Available once you can build the Manhattan Project (Nuclear Fission) and while you remain a single dominant city. Don't build it if you already own the Manhattan Project — it won't convert.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MA_UNLOCK_NOTE">
			<Text>Metropolis Ascendant unlocked. As your Urban [icon:YIELD_POPULATION] Population grows, a single tall city gains escalating bonuses tied to where you research them across the tech and culture trees: more Specialist slots, larger [icon:YIELD_SCIENCE] Science and [icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture adjacency, yields per Population, extra Great Work slots, faster Wonder production, and Suzerain bonuses that scale with the city-states you lead. Build Wonders to enrich the metropolis: adjacent Buildings gain [icon:YIELD_HAPPINESS] Happiness and your Wonders raise the Appeal of the surrounding land - and once you discover a Natural Wonder, [B]Arcadia[/B] awakens: every Breathtaking rural tile flourishes with [icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture, [icon:YIELD_PRODUCTION] Production, [icon:YIELD_HAPPINESS] Happiness, [icon:YIELD_SCIENCE] Science and [icon:YIELD_FOOD] Food, and you may terrace Mountains to work them for [icon:YIELD_PRODUCTION] Production, [icon:YIELD_SCIENCE] Science and [icon:YIELD_CULTURE] Culture. Bonuses fade as you add settlements (Towns included) and end at four.</Text>
		</Row>
	</EnglishText>
</Database>
